Guide to the Goddard Lieberson Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Business files, 1948-1978
  - Institutional memberships, donations and collaborations
    - Stravinsky Festival (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Stuart Ostrow Foundation (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Theatre Development Fund (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Bicentennial Festival (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Capital Historical Society (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Historical Society (Box 52, Folder 11A)
    - Young Audiences (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Travel itineraries, diaries and appointment books
    This subseries documents Goddard Lieberson's business travel from 1970 to 1975. Materials include telephone messages taken during his time away, his secretary's correspondence with hotels and hosts, flight information, and itineraries. On occasion, folders include materials (e.g., programs) related to public events that took place during Lieberson's visits.
    Organized by date.
    - European Classical Conference, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - NY/Alb/NY, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - NY/Alb/NY/NY, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - NY/Chicago/Alb/NY, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - NY/LA/Alb, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - NY/LA/Hawaii/Tokyo, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - LA/St. Louis/NY, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Barbados, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - California, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Cannes, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Norway/LA/NY, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - NY/Frankfurt/Paris, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - NY/Alb/LA/Alb/NY, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - NY/LA/SF/NY, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - NY/Santa Fe/NY, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - NY/San Fran/Tokyo, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Santa Fe/LA/Freeport, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Europe, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - LA, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Tokyo/LA/NY, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - CRI Convention London, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Europe, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Japan, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Kansas City/Santa Fe/Mexico, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - LA/Honolulu/Tokyo, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Convention - Nashville, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Convention - San Francisco, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Convention - U.K., 1973 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - English Convention, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - LA/San Fran/Alb, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - LA/Tokyo, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - London, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - NY/Alb/LA/Alb/NY, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - NY/LA/San Fran, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - NY/New Hampshire, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - NY/Paris/London/Stratford, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - NY/TN/NY, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Barbados, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Convention, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Convention - France, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Convention - L.A., 1974 (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Convention - L.A., 1974 (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - Convention - Vancouver, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - DJ Convention, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - French Convention, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - International Music Industry Conference, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - London/Oslo, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Nashville Sales Meeting, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - NY/Atlanta/Alb/NY, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - NY/FLA/NY, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - NY/London/NY, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - Travel - General Info, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - Vacation - Santa Fe, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - Barbados/Atlanta, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Convention - Atlanta, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Convention - Toronto, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Dartmouth - N.H., 1975 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - LA/Vancouver/NY, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - NY/LA/Cleveland/NY, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - NY/LA/Santa Fe/NY, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - NY/Oslo/Paris/London/Tokyo/LA/NY, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - NY/Wash./LA/NY, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Travel Schedule, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Oslo/Zurich/London, 1976-08-31-1976-10-01 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Travel Documents and Expenses, assorted (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Personal Travel Expenses, assorted (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Itineraries, assorted, 1959-1964 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Diary Pages, 1957-01-1957-09 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Appointment Books, 1959 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Diary, 1977 (Box 54a, Item 1)
    - Diary, 1977 (Box 54a, Item 2)
    - Diary, 1976 (Box 54a, Item 3)
    - Diary, 1975 (Box 54a, Item 4)
    - Address Book (Box 54a, Item 5)
    - Miscellaneous Note Pad (Box 54a, Item 6)
- Audio, video and film, 1962-1977
  [describe outlying dates -- 1943, 1979, 1985]
  Organized by format.
  - Transcription discs and test pressings, 15
    - Side 1: Chorus Line, 1; 12" transcription disc (Box 55, Folder 1)
      "1st copy" written on original sleeve.
    - Side 2: Chorus Line, 1; 12" transcription disc (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Orig. Cast. Proj #2810-2. CHAN-N-2; ASRA N-2. "1st copies" written original sleeve.
    - Untitled, 1976-05-13; 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 3)
      "MQAL 34197-1A, MQBL 34197-1C" written on original sleeve.
    - [unmarked], 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - [unmarked], 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - My Fair Lady Testing Pressing #2, 1976-05-28; 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 6)
      "MQAL-34197-2B, MQBL-34197-2B" written on original sleeve (disc itself is unmarked).
    - My Fair Lady: Side 1 & Side 2, 1976-05-03; 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 7)
      "QBL 34197-1" written on disc.
    - Art Songs, 1; 12" transcription disc (Box 55, Folder 8)
      NW-247 A.v, NW-247 B.v
    - Bebop, 1; 12" transcription disc (Box 55, Folder 9)
      NW-271 A, NW-271-B. Disc is accompanied by "uncorrected" liner notes by Dan Morgenstern.
    - [unmarked], 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - [unmarked], 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - [unmarked], 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - [unmarked], 1; 12" test pressing (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - "Billy," Lena Martell, 1; 7" transcription disc (Box 55, Folder 14)
      7N 45338 A Stereo
    - "Stanley Holloway," It Were All Green Hills, 1; 7" transcription disc (Box 55, Folder 15)
      Stereo 45 RPM
  - Reel-to-reel tapes, 29
    - Myles & Lenny Single, 1974-10-03; Cohen, Myles; Solomon, Lenny; 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips; 2 Track Stereo (Box 56, Reel 1)
      "Can You Give It All to Me"; "Don't Come Crying to Me". Business card for Mickymar Productions inside box.
    - Myles & Lenny Side 1, 1974; Cohen, Myles; Solomon, Lenny; 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips (Box 56, Reel 2)
      "Can You Give It All to Me", "You Let Me Down", "Don't Come Crying to Me", "Easy to Love", "In the Sky". Produced by: Mickymar Productions. Engineered by: John Stewart. All songs BMI.
    - Myles & Lenny Side 2, 1974; Cohen, Myles; Solomon, Lenny; 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips (Box 56, Reel 3)
      "Thingy's Breakdown", "Take Me Back", "Louisiana", "Never Had Time", "Hold On Lovers", "Colours". Produced by: Mickymar Productions. Engineered by: John Stewart. All songs BMI.
    - Lenny & Miles [sic], Cohen, Myles; Solomon, Lenny; 1; 5" reel; 7 1/2 ips (Box 56, Reel 11)
      "Can You Give it All to Me" 04-4069A. "To: Yetnikoff, Walter 5383"
    - Side A, 1 (Box 56, Reel 4)
      "Oilsong", "Up on the Mountain", "In My Own Way", "I See Before Me", "Red Neck Man", "Rachel, Rachel", "Still Be Right", "Sunday Morning - Amazing Jesus".
    - Side B, 1 (Box 56, Reel 5)
      "Biddy Biddy Bye", "Pants Dropping Dance", "And We Danced", "How Can They Hurt You", "War", "You're Changing", "Up You Go", "Fathers and Daughters".
    - Ian Page, 1973-07-16; Page, Ian, 1960-; 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips; 4/4 Trk Stereo (Box 56, Reel 6)
      Side 1: 1. And I Do, 2. Keep On Lovin' Me, 3. Married, 4. Waving Goodbye, 5. If You Had All the Love in the World. Side 2: 1. Annebelle, 2. Dream, 3. Send Me Down Some Love, 4. Hey Time, 5. Everybody's Singing Love Songs
    - Johnny Mathis, 1973-07-09; Mathis, Johnny; 1; 7.5 ips; 1/4 Track (Box 56, Reel 7)
      Side 1 (Track A): 1. I'm Going Home, 2. I'd Rather Be Here With You, 3. Foolish, 4. I'm Stone in Love With You, 5. And I Think That's What I'll Do. Side 2 (Track B): 1. Life is a Song Worth Singing, 2. A Baby's Born, 3. Sweet Child, 4. Stop Look Listen to Your Heart, 5. I Just Wanted to Be Me.
      General
      copy of copy. Project 105961
    - Mormon Folksong Tapes from Dr. Thomas Cheney, 1; 7.5 ips (Box 56, Reel 8)
      "Folk Songs for the Mormon Legacy Album, Recorded in Salt Lake City, Utah" 1. Charlie Knell's Wedding, 2. Mottos on the Wall, 3. The Grecian Bend (sic), 4. Pioneer Day 1870, 5. Seagulls and Crickets.
    - The Magnificent Nonsense, Malloch, William F.; 1; 1/4 track stereo; 3.75 ips (both ways) (Box 56, Reel 9)
    - The Magnificent Nonsense, a Tragical-Comical History of the War to End All Wars 1914-1918, Malloch, William F.; 1; 5" reel; 3.75 ips; 1/4 track stereo (Box 56, Reel 10)
      Side one - Europe, Side two - America
    - Corrected Pulcinella Narration, 1979-04-29; 1; 5" reel; 7.5 ips (Box 56, Reel 12)
    - Peter's Film Score, 1968-10-18; 1; 7.5 Mono (Box 56, Reel 13)
    - Julliard Commencement - Lieberson, 1; 7" reel (Box 56, Reel 14)
    - American Musical Theatre with Goddard Lieberson, 1962-04-15; 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips (Box 56, Reel 15)
      WCBS TV 11:30-12:15 AM, Rockhill Recording
    - Billy Liar - John Barry, Don Black, Barry, John, 1933-2011; Black, Don; 1; 11" reel (Box 57, Reel 1)
      Side One: 1. And Another Bloody Thing, 2. Some of Us Belong to the Stars, 3. Shadrock Duxbury, 4. Happy to be Themselves, 5. The Witch, 6. Lies! Lies! Lies!, 7. He'll Grow Out of It, 8. It Were All Green Hills, 9. Billy Fisher. Side two: 1. Billy, 2. I Missed the Last Rainbow, 3. Any Minute Now (Barbara's Version), 4. Any Minute Now (Rita's Version), 5. Any Minute Now (Short version), 6. That Wouldn't Be You, 7. Som eof Us Belong to the Stars (reprise).
    - Tribute to Goddard Lieberson - Broadway Original Cast Excerpts, Reel One, 1; 11" reel; 7.5 ips; Stereo 2 track (Box 57, Reel 2)
      On the Town (Overture: New York, New York), Bells Are Ringing (Overture: Just in Time), The Sound of Music (Climb Every Mountain), Flower Drum Song (Overture: I Enjoy Being a Girl), West Side Story (Overture: Tonight), The Pajama Game (Overture: Hey There), South Pacific (Overture: Some Enchanted Evening), Gypsy (Overture: Everything's Comin' Up Roses), Pal Joey (Overture: I Could Write a Book).
    - Tribute to Goddard Lieberson - Broadway Original Cast Excerpts, Reel Two, 1; 11" reel; 7.5 ips; Stereo 2 track (Box 57, Reel 3)
      My Fair Lady (Overture: On the Street Where You Live, I Could Have Danced All Night, Get Me to the Church on Time, The Rain in Spain), Candide - Overture, Sweet Charity - (Overture, If My Friends Could See Me Now), Camelot (Overture, If Ever I Should Leave You), Mame, Cabaret (Finale - Caberet), A Little Night Music (Overture), A Chorus Line (One - Finale).
    - Tribute to Goddard Lieberson - Broadway Original Cast Excerpts, Reel Two, 1; 11" reel; 7.5 ips; Stereo 2 tracks (Box 57, Reel 4)
      possibly a copy
    - G. Lieberson Intros, 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips; Mono full track (Box 57, Reel 5)
      Spoken introductions from concert with John Hammond (excerpts)
    - Jazz at the Best. Interview with Mr. Goddard Lieberson, 1966-10; 1; 7" reel; 7.5 ips (Box 57, Reel 6)
      Recorded in New York City. Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, Serial No. 40496. H. Whiston.
    - Project Sixty Goddard Lieberson WBT Radio Reel I, 1; 7" Reel (Box 58, Reel Item 1)
    - Project Sixty Goddard Lieberson WBT Radio Reel I, 1; 7" Reel (Box 58, Reel 2)
    - Project Sixty Goddard Lieberson WBT Radio Reel II, 1; 7" Reel (Box 58, Reel 3)
    - Project Sixty Goddard Lieberson WBT Radio Reel II, 1; 7" Reel (Box 58, Reel 4)
    - CBC. Wed. Night. Schoenberg Documentary #1, 1962-09-09; 1; 7" Reel; 7.5 ips (Box 58, Reel 5)
      1 SET E, 56958
    - CBC. Wed. Night. Schoenberg Documentary #2, 1962-09-09; 1; 7" Reel; 7.5 ips (Box 58, Reel 6)
      2 SET E, 56958
    - CBC. Wed. Night. Schoenberg Documentary #3, 1962-09-09; 1; 7" Reel; 7.5 ips (Box 58, Reel 7)
      3 SET E, 56958
    - CBC. Wed. Night. Schoenberg Documentary #4, 1962-09-09; 1; 7" Reel; 7.5 ips (Box 58, Reel 8)
      4 SET E, 56958
  - Audiocassettes, 3
    - GL WOR, 1943-03-31; 1; TDK D90 (Box 57, Item 7)
      Morton Gould; CRESTA BLANCA. WOR 9:15-10:00PM
    - NY/NARAS-A&R Luncheon, 1985-10-02; 1 (Box 57, Item 8)
      "From the desk of Milt Gabler" Side 1: Maher and Gabler; Goddard Lieberson/Ahmet Ertegun. Side 2: Tom Frost and Mitch Miller.
    - GL, 1977-12-08; 1; Norelco microcassette (Box 57, Item 9)
  - Videotapes, 16
    - Tribute to Goddard Lieberson, 1975-08-05; 1; Scotch Umatic (Box 59, Item 1)
    - Lieberson Tribute, 1977-10-19; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 2)
      HQVT 7, Tape Number 9
    - Lieberson Tribute, 1977-10-19; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 3)
      HQVT 8, Tape Number 9
    - Barry Manilow Special, 1976-12-03; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 4)
      ABC special
    - They Said It With Music/Everybody Rag with Me/Alexander's Ragtime, 1976-08-23; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 5)
      Segs for Goddard Lieberson (on side)
    - WCBS-TV News - From the Newsroom with Rolland Smith and Dave Marash, 1976-10-20; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 6)
      Pat Collins Review of "Poor Murderer"
    - They Said It With Music: Yankee Doodle to Ragtime Part 1, 1977-07-04; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 7)
      Created and Produced by Goddard Lieberson, CBS Television Network, Part 1
    - They Said It With Music: Yankee Doodle to Ragtime Part 2, 1977-07-04; 1; Umatic (Box 59, Item 8)
      Created and Produced by Goddard Lieberson, CBS Television Network, Part 2
    - They Said It With Music, 1976-08-23; 1; FujiFilm Umatic (Box 60, Item 1)
      Reel 2 of 3
    - They Said It With Music, 1976-08-23 (Box 60, Item 1a)
      Reel 1 of 3
    - They Said It With Music, 1976-08-23 (Box 60, Item 1b)
    - CBS - They Said It With Music - New Edit, 1976-08-04; 1; Umatic (Box 60, Item 2)
      Notes on Side do not correspond to not on cassette - "Bi-Cent. Music Roll 1, 7.6.76" written on case
    - Said It With Music [sic], Reel 2, 1976-12-17; 1; Ampex, Umatic (Box 60, Item 3)
      VC-8699, Tape Length 60
    - Said It With Music [sic], Reel 2, 1976-12-17; 1; Ampex, Umatic (Box 60, Item 4)
      VC-8700, Tape Length 60
    - They Said It With Music, Part I, 1976-11-14; 1; Ampex, Umatic (Box 60, Item 5)
      Note on side of case: VC-8229, V7 C4, Tape Length 60
    - They Said It With Music, Part II, 1976-11-14; 1; Ampex, Umatic (Box 60, Item 6)
      Note on side of case: VC-8084, Tape Length 60
    - They Said It With Music, Reel I, 1977-01-23; 1; Ampex, Umatic (Box 60, Item 7)
      For Rita Barton - CBS - NY. VC 9191, Tape Length 60
    - They Said It With Music, Reel II, 1977-01-23; 1; Ampex, Umatic (Box 60, Item 8)
      For Rita Burton - CBS - NY, VC 9184, Tape Length 60
  - Film reels, 3
    - "Goddard Lieberson", circa 1965; 1; 16mm film reel (Box 61)
    - Budapest String Quartet #33, circa 1965; 1; 16mm Film Reel (Box 62)
      Serial Number 621018-06A
    - Richard Rogers "Play Back" Part II, circa 1965; 1; 16mm Film Reel (Box 63)
      Unedited Show, 17:00 Mins. Do Not Cut Reference Print Only
- Music and art, 1930-1964
  - Music by Goddard Lieberson
    Includes sketches, pencil manuscripts, and a few published scores.
    Organized alphabetically by title.
    - Abalone (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Advertisement and Parade (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Air (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Alborado del etcetera (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Alone (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - The Ambitious Cellist (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Ancient Dance (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - The Barge (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Berceuse for 2 cellos (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Berceuse for Two Little Girls M and E (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Broadway Show (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Chanson D'Autumne (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Chassidic Dance (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Christmas Eve (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - The Cowboy's Lament (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Cradle Song (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Dance (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Dance a Waltz, Simply, Sentimentally, Sweetly,with Childish Candour (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Dance Under a Tree (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - East Wind (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Der Flug nach San Franzisko fallt heut' aus (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Flute Recital (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - For Armeme who likes Bach (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - A German Gramophone Record - 1939 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - God's Trombones: eight songs for baritone voice (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - Gramophone - 1912 (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Great is the Day (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Green Apples (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - A Guitar for Xmas (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - Han Laengta (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - Hatter and Hare (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - Here now is the answer (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - Homage to Handel Suite for Strings (Box 64, Folder 33)
    - I love you (Box 64, Folder 34)
    - Incidental Music for a Puppet Performance of Alice In Wonderland (Box 64, Folder 35)
    - Inscriptions for Cello and Piano (Box 64, Folder 36)
    - Italian [Prime time] (Box 64, Folder 37)
    - Ladies In Retirement (Box 64, Folder 38)
    - Lament of a Shropshire Lad upon Separation from his Beloved (Box 64, Folder 39)
    - Love is a Sickness (Box 64, Folder 40)
    - Love Song (Box 64, Folder 41)
    - Lullaby for baby not yet born (Box 64, Folder 42)
    - Mardrigal for 3 voices (Box 64, Folder 43)
    - Mein Herz Spruhrt Etwas (Box 64, Folder 44)
    - Melodie (Box 64, Folder 45)
    - Melody VI -Sarcastic (Box 64, Folder 46)
    - Mermaid (Box 64, Folder 47)
    - Moorish Street Carnivale (Box 64, Folder 48)
    - Musical Comedy II (Box 64, Folder 49)
    - A Nervous Waltz (Box 65, Folder 50)
    - Night Club (Box 65, Folder 51)
    - Nite Club Singer (Box 65, Folder 52)
    - Nine Melodies for Solo Piano (Box 65, Folder 53)
    - Nine Two-Line Poems of Ezra Pound Set to Music (Box 65, Folder 54)
    - No Sound of Music (Box 65, Folder 55)
    - No Time (Box 65, Folder 56)
    - Opening Time (Box 65, Folder 57)
    - Passacaille (3 versions) (Box 65, Folder 58)
    - Passocoglio (Box 65, Folder 59)
    - Petit Plaisir (Box 65, Folder 60)
    - Piano Pieces for Advanced Children or Retarded Adults (Box 65, Folder 61)
    - A Piano Sketch: Penguin Island (Box 65, Folder 62)
    - Pig and Pepper (Box 65, Folder 63)
    - Prelude (Box 65, Folder 64)
    - Preludes (Box 65, Folder 65)
    - Quintette for Oboe, Basson, Viola, Cello, Piano (Box 65, Folder 66)
    - Six Modern Painters (full score, piano, percussion, Gauguin sketch) (Box 65, Folder 67)
    - Six Modern Painters (strings and harp) (Box 65, Folder 68)
    - Six Modern Painters (woodwinds and brass) (Box 65, Folder 69)
    - Six Modern Painters (bound piano score) (Box 65, Folder 70)
    - Slow Dance (Box 65, Folder 71)
    - Song of the Jack Hammer Man (Box 65, Folder 72)
    - Street Scenes (Box 65, Folder 73)
    - String Quartet (3 bound full scores with markings, violin II & viola parts) (Box 66, Folder 74)
    - String Quartet (Oxford University Press full score and parts) (Box 66, Folder 75)
    - Tango (piano, celeste, percussion) (Box 66, Folder 76)
    - Tango (strings and harp) (Box 66, Folder 77)
    - Tango (woodwinds and brass) (Box 66, Folder 78)
    - Tango (Orchestral Scores - Oversized) (Box 82, Folder 3)
      Three manuscript orchestral scores - One titled "Satire in Tango Rhythm"
    - Three Songs In the Old Modes (written to please an old lady) (Box 66, Folder 79)
    - Toccata (2 versions) (Box 66, Folder 80)
    - Toccata for 1 Piano 4 Hands (Box 66, Folder 81)
    - The Tractor (Box 66, Folder 82)
    - Two Songs - (written to please an old lady) (Box 66, Folder 83)
    - The Unnecessary Conversationalist (Box 66, Folder 84)
    - Valse Franc(a)ise (Box 66, Folder 85)
    - Valse Rusee de Snegurochka (Box 66, Folder 86)
    - Violin Concerto (Box 66, Folder 87)
    - Waltzes (Box 66, Folder 88)
    - Waltz: Ashes of Roses or Tragedie d'Amour (Box 66, Folder 89)
    - [Westim] (Box 66, Folder 90)
    - Yellow Poodle (Box 66, Folder 91)
    - Transcriptions (Box 67, Folder 92)
    - Orchestral sketches (Box 67, Folder 93)
    - Miscellaneous songs (Box 67, Folder 94)
    - Miscellaneous sketches and fragments (Box 67, Folder 95)
    - Miscellaneous sketches and fragments (Box 67, Folder 96)
    - Miscellaneous sketches and fragments (Box 67, Folder 97)
    - Miscellaneous sketches and fragments (Box 67, Folder 98)
  - Music by Others
    - Assorted music by others (Box 67, Folder 99)
      Includes childhood composition books by Peter Lieberson and Brigitta Hartwig.
    - Romero, Aldemaro - El Gavilan (Oversized) (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Copland, Aaron - Inscape, 1968 (Box 67c, Folder 1)
      Dedication to Lieberson (written by Aaron Copland) on title page.
    - Gershwin, George - Porgy and Bess, 1935 (Box 67c, Folder 2)
      Piano and vocal score. Includes annotations.
  - Artwork by Goddard Lieberson (Box 68)
    Contains sketches, drawings, caricatures and holiday cards.
  - Artwork by others
    - Prints collected by Goddard Lieberson (Box 67, Folder 100)
    - "Goddard Lieberson, As Orpheus", 1964 (Folder 67a)
      Unframed painting by Veniero Colasanti (1910-1996) and John Moore (b. 1924).
    - Framed painting of Albert Schweitzer by Feliks Topolski (Box 67b)
    - Williams - "The Kremlin Moscow" (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Pablo [?] - "Rio", 1957 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Ahrens - "Vera Zorina", 1944 (Box 82, Folder 4)
- Writings by Goddard Lieberson, 1930-1975
  This series contains drafts and published copies of articles, essays, and creative projects by Goddard Lieberson over the course of his career. Topics include the recording industry, Lieberson's work at Columbia, and op-ed style critiques of music and art for publications such as The Saturday Review and Modern Music. Creative projects include Lieberson's novel, Three for Bedroom "C" (1947). Note that published reviews of Lieberson's writings (as well as his recording projects) can be found in the "Writings by Others" series.
  The "Essays and Speeches" and "Plays, poetry and books" subseries are organized alphabetically, while "Published writings and newspaper columns" is organized chronologically.
  - Essays and speeches
    - The American Record Guide - 30th Anniversary (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - The American Revolution (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - A Purely Argumentative Consideration of So-Called Musical-Therapy without Benefit of Clinical Study (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Arthur Hornblow (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Artist Profiles & Album Notes (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Badmen (Introduction) (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - The Billboard - Paul Ackerman (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Billboard's IMIC 5, 1974-1978 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Bruno Walter in Conversation with Arnold Michaels (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - CBS Convention (San Francisco), 1973 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - CBS Speeches (Assorted) (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1967-02-23 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Columbia Literary Series (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - The Constitution - A Guide in our National and to our International Socio-Economic Development (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Copland: Billy the Kid; Rodeo (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - The Discriminating Listener (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - A Discussion of Tschaikowsky's Fourth Symphony (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - The (Persistent) Echo (The Reporter), 1954-07-06 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - The Embarrassed Collector (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Facade (with Dame Edith Sitwell) (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Father Damasus Memorial, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Frank Sinatra Conducts Music of Alec Wilder (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Hal Holbrook in Mark Twain Tonight! (Box 69, Folder 23)